VINIT KUMAR

$\begin{array}{c} \text{https://vinitkumar.me} \\ \text{vinit1414.08@bitmesra.ac.in} \\ +91\text{-}8554862210 \end{array}$

Summary

Vinit is a Senior Software Engineer at Social Schools B.V. He has spent more than 5 years building Social Network for Schools, Multi-tenant CMS, APIs and modern web front-end using React and Angular. He is an active member of the Free and Open Source Software community and has contributed to many projects. He is an avid book reader and reads a lot of technical books for fun.

EDUCATION

B.E Civil Engineering

July 2008 - Sep 2012

Birla Institute of Technology, Mesra

CAREER HISTORY

Senior Software Engineer, Social Schools B.V., Pune

Feb 2013 - Present

App development Consultant, gadgetizor.com and digitizor.com

Summer 2011 - Jan 2013

• Worked on the design and scaling of WordPress based high traffic sites.

JavaScript Developer, Worked on a E-Commerce based Chrome Extension and extension listed on Coderwall.com http://coderwall.com/api Sep 2012 - Jan 2012

• Wrote a chrome extension integrating Facebook APIs and E-Commerce site Flipkart.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Python, JavaScript/Node.js, Go, C, Obj-C, Rust, Tex, Java

Frontend Frameworks: React, Angular, Backbone Database: PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, SQLite

Version Control: Git, Mercurial

Backend Frameworks: Django, Flask, Express.js

Mobile Development: Android, iOS(minor experience), React Native

Operating Systems: macOS, Linux, Windows

Important links

Github: https://github.com/vinitkumar

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/vinitatlinkedin/

Twitter: https://twitter.com/vinitkme

LEADERSHIP ACTIVITIES

Administrator, In-Charge: Linux User Group, (Bit Mesra)

June 2011 - May 2012

Administrator: Web and DC server, (Bit Mesra)

June 2011- May 2012

BLOG

Gotchacode Tech-blog covering topics related to web and Open Source. https://gotchacode.com